# **Daehwa Kim**

407 South Craig Street, Pittsburgh, PA 15213 daehwak@andrew.cmu.edu • +1 415 937 4111 • https://daehwa.github.io

### RESEARCH INTERESTS

My research goal is creating naturalistic and intimate computing experience by exploring high-fidelity interface technologies. This interest can be applied for various domains, particularly wearable computing, mobile computing and extended reality environments. I presented several papers at ACM CHI and UIST and have been recognized with two Best Paper Honorable Mention awards at CHI.

### **EDUCATION**

# Ph.D. student, Carnegie Mellon University, School of Computer Science,

**Human-Computer Interaction Institute** 

Advised by Prof. Chris Harrison at Future Interfaces Group

Sep 2022 – Current

# M.Sc., KAIST, School of Computing

Mar 2019 – Feb 2021

- Advised by Prof. Geehyuk Lee at Human-Computer Interaction Lab
- Thesis: "OddEyeCam: Sensing Technique for Body-Centric Peephole Interaction Using WFoV RGB and NFoV Depth Cameras" (2020 Best Thesis Award)

# B.S., UNIST, Electrical and Computer Engineering

Mar 2015 - Feb 2019

- Computer Science and Engineering (Major) and Electrical Engineering (Minor)
- Entered with top honors.
- Summer session program, UAL (University of the Arts London), London, UK

Jul 2018

### **PUBLICATIONS**

- [1] <u>Daehwa Kim</u>, and Chris Harrison, "EtherPose: Continuous Hand Pose Tracking with Wrist-Worn Antenna Impedance" in *Proceedings of the 35th Annual ACM Symposium on User Interface Software and Technology*, Bend, Oregon, USA, Oct 2022.
- [2] Craig Shultz, <u>Daehwa Kim</u>, Karan Ahuja, and Chris Harrison, "TriboTouch: Micro-Patterned Surfaces for Low Latency Touchscreens" in *Proceedings of the 2022 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems*, New Orleans, LA, USA, Apr 2022. Best Paper Honorable Mention Award; Top 5%
- [3] <u>Daehwa Kim</u>, Keunwoo Park, and Geehyuk Lee, "AtaTouch: Robust Finger Pinch Detection for a VR Controller Using RF Return Loss" in *Proceedings of the 2021 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems*, Yokohama, Japan. <u>Best Paper Honorable Mention Award</u>; Top 5%
- [4] <u>Daehwa Kim</u>, Keunwoo Park, and Geehyuk Lee, "OddEyeCam: A Sensing Technique for Body-Centric Peephole Interaction Using WFoV RGB and NFoV Depth Cameras" in *Proceedings of the 33rd Annual ACM Symposium on User Interface Software and Technology*, Virtual Event, USA, Oct 2020.
- [5] Keunwoo Park, <u>Daehwa Kim</u>, Seongkook Heo, and Geehyuk Lee, "MagTouch: Robust Finger Identification for a Smartwatch Using a Magnet Ring and a Built-in Magnetometer" in *Proceedings of the 2020 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems*, Honolulu, Hawaii, USA, Apr 2020.

# AWARDS & HONORS

#### Best Paper Honorable Mention Award, ACM CHI 2022

May 2022

 Craig Shultz, <u>Daehwa Kim</u>, Karan Ahuja, and Chris Harrison, "TriboTouch: Micro-Patterned Surfaces for Low Latency Touchscreens" in *Proceedings of the 2022 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems*, New Orleans, LA, USA, Apr 2022.

# Best Paper Honorable Mention Award, ACM CHI 2021

May 2021

 <u>Daehwa Kim</u>, Keunwoo Park, and Geehyuk Lee, "AtaTouch: Robust Finger Pinch Detection for a VR Controller Using RF Return Loss" in *Proceedings of the 2021 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems*, Yokohama, Japan.

# Best Master's Thesis Award, KAIST School of Computing

Feb 2021

 Thesis: "OddEyeCam: Sensing Technique for Body-Centric Peephole Interaction Using WFoV RGB and NFoV Depth Cameras"

# RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

# Future Interfaces Group, Carnegie Mellon University

• Full-time Research Associate, Human-Computer Interaction Institute

Sep 2021 – Apr 2022

• Project: Exploring new touch input and human pose tracking technologies.

• Advisor: Prof. Chris Harrison

#### HCI Lab. KAIST

Undergraduate Research Student, School of Computing

Mar 2018 - Jun 2018

• Project: PCB design for a hand gesture sensing wristband.

· Advisor: Prof. Geehyuk Lee

• Focus: human-computer interaction, PCB design, physical prototyping

# ACADEMIC SERVICE

### Reviewer

■ UIST '22, CHI '22 LBW, IMWUT '21, CHI '21 LBW

## **PROJECTS**

## **Audio Hero**

Sep 2019 – Dec 2019

Sound-based danger detection system using VGGish deep learning model

• Skills: Deep learning, Signal processing

**VRone** 

Sep 2018 – Dec 2018

3-dimensional force feedback in VR using a personal and commercial drone

• Skills: Unity C# programming, Android programming

System Light 2.0 @ ETRI

Jan 2018 - Mar 2018

• Smart Home project - Building IoT system for lights

Skills: Computer network, Natural language processing

**VibCat** 

Oct 2017 - Dec 2017

Vibration Categorization for Input & Interaction

• Skills: Machine learning, Android programming

# Finger joystick interaction

Feb 2017 – Nov 2017

 Interaction technique to support finger's directional input using capacitive image of a smartwatch's touchscreen

• Skills: Machine learning, Android programming

#### Poem a moment

Mar 2017 – Jun 2017

• An android software that shows Yoon Dongju's poems on the wallpaper

• Available on Google Play store (download 1000+)

• Skills: Android programming

## **TUIT Android Lecture**

Jun 2016 – Sep 2016

Android development lecture provided to TUIT university students

• Skills: Android programming, Object-oriented programming

### Mr.Bill

Jun 2016 – Jul 2016

Algorithm and system to provide optimal Dutch pay way

• Available on Google Play store (download 500+)

• Skills: Android programming, Graph theory